STEVE POWELL

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

linkedin.com/in/steve-powel work.stevepowell@gmail.com Albertville, Quebec, Canada

SUMMARY

I am a passionate software engineer with good experience in different fields of development. Over the past decade, I've contributed to a number of projects as a full-stack, back-end, and front-end developer. I am currently focusing on JavaScript, TypeScript and PHP based development. I am always looking for new challenges and technologies while delivering high-quality solutions.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

Faculty of Engineering, University of Alberta | 2007 - 2011

LANGUAGES

- JavaScript
- GraphQL
- TypeScript
- PHP

BACK-END

- Node.js
- Loopback.io
- Express.js
- Symfony
- Nest.js
- Codelgniter
- Laravel

FRONT-END

- React
- Vuetify
- Angular
- Nuxt.js
- Vue
- Tailwind CSS
- Next.js
- jQuery
- Gatsby
- SCSS

OTHER

- Agile-Scrum/
 Docker Kanban
- Kubernetes
- AWS
- GCP
- CI/CD

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Self-Employed | September 2018 - PRESENT Quebec, Canada

- Developed multiples serverless web apps; using Node.js, React, AWS API Gateway, and AWS Lambda, EC2, Route 53
- Worked on the frontend part a storage management solution to meet any requirement based on Vue.js, Svelte
- Developed pixel-perfect and high-perfomance healthcare application with React.js, Node.js and Strapi
- Created a HOC architecture to reuse common GraphQL functionality for listing and filtering
- Developed price analysis platform depend on Price api and Google Merchant api with Angular and Node
- Developed Typescript reusable components and services that are consumed by REST API using
- Component-based architecture

Stacks: Node.js, React, Vue.js, Angular, Svelte, GraphQL, AWS, **REST API**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ConvrtX | Full-Time

January 2016 - June 2018 | Toronto, Canada

- Developed SaaS platform using React(hook), Redux, Material-UI/Ant-Design
- Developed a highly visible web-app for the people operations team to manage all information related to the organization from structure to compensation to performance feedback using a Vue front-end and a Node back-end with a MySQL database

- Developed a real estate trading system that enables users to mark up real estate, parcels, and further details
- Developed a custom eCommerce platform that worked as a shop, taking all products from advertisers based on Laravel
- Wrote a front-end web app from scratch using Vue.js, VueX to significantly improve the bounce rate after the initial launch of the site

Stacks: React, Redux, Node.js, Vue.js, VueX, Laravel, MySQL

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Inetum | Full-Time

April 2014 - November 2015 | Saint-Quentin, France

- Developed front-end part of a case management platform using Angular
- Implemented a large front-end SaaS application using Angular according to wireframes as well as a backend in Nest.js/Node.js
- Designed database architecture and API based on GraphQL, PostgreSQL, NestJS
- Integrated a real-time dashboard for trading information using WebSocket
- Managing the Migration, Seeding, Eloquent model, Routing, Authentication, Middleware, ORM, Unit testing, Artisan in Laravel
- Set up the AWS environment (AWS S3, AWS CloudFront, and AWS EC2)

Technologies: Angular, Nest.js, React, Laravel, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, AWS, WebSocket

WEB DEVELOPER

Renault Software Factory | Contract Full-Time

January 2012 - December 2013 | Boulogne, France

- Prototyped and implemented Node.js and Socket.IO communication, enabling real-time application capabilities
- Optimized the front-end portion to make a fully functional and performant website using Webpack and many other compressing tools
- Extensively used JavaScript for adding dynamic web content to Web Pages
- Developed Front-end UI using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Have used JavaScript and jQuery for building several functionalities of the application

Stacks: Node.js, Socket.io, Webpack, JavaScript HTML, CSS, jQuery